Parsa Abadi . Jarvis Consulting

I am a motivated team player who is curious, organized, and committed to following established rules and protocols in all aspects of my work and personal life. I constantly attempt to contribute to a productive and encouraging work environment because communication and teamwork are essential to success. I recently graduated from McMaster University with a Bachelor of Applied Science in Honours Computer Science with a strong academic record. I offer knowledge from my studies and experience to the software industry. I add value to any team with my understanding of documentation, user requirements, and software development. In addition, I am a proud and dedicated member of my city, competing in competitive chess and playing volleyball for a city-wide team. These passions bring balance to my life and a fresh perspective to my work. I am excited for the opportunity to prove myself as a valuable team member in the software development industry.

Skills

Proficient: Python, RDBMS/SQL, Linux/Bash, Agile/Scrum, Git/Github

Competent: Java, NodeJS, Angular/React, AWS, HTML/CSS, Docker, REST APIs

Familiar: C#, C/C++, Haskell, Spring, Ruby, ASP.NET

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/Jarvis-Consulting-Group/jarvis data eng-parsaabadi

Linux Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The Linux nodes in a cluster are monitored for hardware specifications and usage, with the data stored in a PostgreSQL database. The database runs in a Docker container, configured with a Bash script to allow data to be collected from the machines with Linux commands (such as lscpu, vmstat, and psql) and scheduled to run every minute using crontab to allow for continuous monitoring.

Highlighted Projects

Web Development Local Business Review App [GitHub]: The 4WW3 Project is a website that allows users to browse and contribute reviews of geographically based destinations. The website utilizes a combination of technologies to provide a seamless user experience. The front-end of the website is built using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, which are used to create the layout, styling and interactive features of the website. On the back-end, the website utilizes PHP to handle server-side tasks such as user authentication and data management. Additionally, the website uses .htaccess to accept php for secure user authorization and Git for version control. The site also uses Jquery and Bootstrap for responsive design and has some animations implemented using animate.css.

Python Custom Compiler [GitHub]: The project involved modifying a pre-existing P0 Compiler to include new features such as universal quantifiers, array builders, set builders, and existential quantifiers. These extensions were implemented by modifying files located in the src folder and adding new files required to extend the original P0 compiler capabilities. These new features allow for the use of quantified expressions in the P0 language, similar to those found in languages like Python, where they can be implemented through external libraries or custom designs. The project aims to enhance the P0 compiler's capabilities by adding support for universal and existential quantifiers, array builders, and set builders.

SprayPost [GitHub]: Spray Post is an innovative communication app that allows users to connect with others in close proximity using a custom engine, Swift, and cloud services. It uses location-based services to identify nearby users and enables real-time communication through text, audio, and video messages, and even voice and video calls. The app also includes features such as creating and joining groups, a built-in social media platform, and sharing location with friends and family. Additionally, Spray Post prioritizes user security and privacy, with customizable profiles and settings. With its many functionalities, Spray Post is an easy and efficient way for users to communicate with those in close proximity.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2023-present): Joined as a Technical Consultant, I have gained experience in new technologies such as Java, Python, SQL, and Spring by working on projects in an Agile/Scrum environment. These technologies are used in the professional workplace for clients.

Research Engineer, McScert (2021-2022): Led the team in maintaining and regularly updating documentation for pods using JIRA. I also collected user requirements for building and maintaining code for tools, and applied principles of

safety engineering to software development in a model-driven environment. This resulted in a boost of 10% development efficiency through testing for bugs. I conducted regular team meetings to share project status, issues, and ideas, rapidly prototyped new capabilities to confirm feasibility, and deployed inter-device communications such as SPI, I2C, and UART. Additionally, I re-designed the auto-layout system for the framework resulting in 20% better readability for testing software.

Education

McMaster University (2018-2022), B.A.Sc. Honours, Computer Science, Department of Engineering - Dean's List: Was on the Dean's list by achieving a term GPA above 3.5 - The Presidential Entrance Scholarship: Given to students entering McMaster University, is awarded to those who have achieved a minimum grade point average of 3.7/4.0.

Miscellaneous

- Energetic member of the Richmond Hill Volleyball team.
- Actively participating in chess tournaments.
- Painting (Realism, Oil, Photorealism)